Women had a decisive say in Huayuan City
花垣城女人當家
while men had it in Xuanhu City.
玄虎城男人當家
The two cities had always been at odds.
兩城歷來不和
Xuanhu was defeated
一場惡戰之後
after a fierce battle,
玄虎落敗
so their Young Master Han Shuo had to marry
只好派少主韓爍和親
into Huayuan City and live there.
入贅花垣
I heard Xuanhu City's Young Master
聽說玄虎城的少城主
will marry one of our princesses.
來我們花垣城聯姻
I wonder which one will marry him.
也不知道會許給哪位郡主
Men have the decisive say in Xuanhu City,
玄虎城男人當家
but in Huayuan City,
哪像咱們花垣城
women are superior to men.
女子為尊
Our officials are women.
女子為官
Our City Owner is a woman.
女子做城主
All men are boors
男人都是莽夫
and know nothing about high-quality life.
哪裡懂得過日子
Look at them.
你看他們
To get the black stone mine,
為了個烏石礦
they even agreed to send their Young Master here as a hostage.
把自己家少城主都抵給咱們了
Look.
你們快看
He's a handsome young man.
長得倒是眉清目秀的
Pitifully, he has a heart disease.
可惜呀 患有心疾
All doctors said that
看過的大夫啊
he couldn't live to 20.
都說活不過二十
He's going to be 19.
這眼看就十九了
Why did Xuanhu City
玄虎城
send a dying guy here?
送個快死的人過來幹什麼
It bodes ill.
真是晦氣
Let's go.
走走走
Move away.
快走開
Get lost. You. All of you get lost.
閃開 說你呢 都閃開
Get her. Move away.
追上她 讓開
Get out of the way.
讓開 閃開 讓開
the Dragon Bone was Huayuan City's rare treasure.
龍骨 是花垣城祕寶
It could cure all diseases and it was the only one of its kind.
可治百病 僅此一根
The main reason why Han Shuo agreed to marry into Huayuan City
韓爍入贅花垣的重要原因
was to get the Dragon Bone.
就是為了得到龍骨
To reach his goal,
為達目的
he tried to get Chen Chuchu, the Second Princess of Huayuan City, into trouble,
他暗中設計了一場英雄救美
so that he could save her
想與花垣城二郡主陳楚楚
and she'd fall in love with him.
一見鍾情
After that, he'd use her to get the Dragon Bone.
再利用她 騙取龍骨
Who are you?
你是何人
Han Shuo, the Young Master of Xuanhu City.
玄虎城少城主 韓爍
You're the one
你就是那個
who'll marry into Huayuan City?
來我們花垣城入贅的韓爍
You're good-looking.
小模樣長得還挺標緻
Clean him up
把他洗乾淨
and send him to my mansion tonight.
今晚送到我府上
Your Highness,
三公主
his marriage to you needs approval from your mother.
此人婚配是要經過城主親自下令
Taking him back like this...
當街強搶
...is against the rules.
於禮不合
If your mother knows about it...
這城主知道了
Since my childhood, there has been nothing I can't get.
自幼沒有我陳芊芊要不來的東西
The Third princess?
三公主
He's just the Young Master of Xuanhu City.
不就是玄虎城少城主嗎
I'm going to ask for my mother's permission to marry him.
我這就向母親請令與他成親
There is no time like the present.
擇日不如撞日
I'll marry him tomorrow.
明日大婚
May I know who you are?
敢問姑娘是
I'm the Third Princess of Huayuan City.
花垣城三公主
Chen Qianqian.
陳芊芊
Third...
三
What to do?
怎麼辦
Young Master.
少君哪
Are you having a heart attack again?
你是不是又發作了
Take the medicine.
快把藥吃了吧
What's wrong?
你怎麼了
Hold on.
等會兒
Take your time.
慢點吃
I've had heart disease since my childhood. I often suffer from heart attacks.
我自幼心疾纏身 不時發作
Doctors said I'll die at 20.
大夫斷言我二十歲就會撒手人寰
I'm afraid our Young Master doesn't have the luck to stay with you.
少君怕是無福消受您的青睞了
Please take back your words.
還請三公主收回成命
It's something about the two cities.
事關兩城聯姻
It'll be terrible if he dies.
鬧出人命就不好了
You're terminally ill?
快病死了
In this case,
既然如此
take him to my mansion
那不還趁人活著
while he's still alive.
趕緊送入我府中
Wait.
慢著
As the saying goes,
俗話說得好
nothing forcibly done is going to be agreeable.
強扭的瓜不甜
We need to give it a go at least.
甜不甜的啃一口不就知道了
Cut the crap.
用得著你說
Get prepared when you arrive at the post house.
到了驛站好好準備一下
I'll marry you tomorrow.
明日迎娶大婚
Count yourself unlucky
遇上我
to meet me.
算你倒黴
Your Highness.
三公主
Obviously, she's taking him for marriage by force.
這分明是搶親
Oh no. He's going to marry the Third Princess.
居然許了三公主
She's the greatest evildoer.
這位可是混世魔王
She's spoiled by her mother.
被城主寵壞了
Look. The young man is in poor health.
你看看這少君的身體不太好
I wonder how long he can survive
也不知道在三公主手裡
if he stays with the Third Princess.
能熬過幾天
I bet he'll die soon.
活不久嘍 活不久嘍
Let's go.
走走走
Alright. Go back.
都散了 散了 散了
Young Master,
少君
it's beyond our expectations.
計劃有變
Rumor has it that
傳聞中這陳芊芊
Chen Qianqian is unreasonable and ridiculous.
蠻不講理 荒唐無度
And she has no regard for laws.
是目無法紀
She is illiterate
斗大的字不識一筐不說
and she suffers from Princess Syndrome.
還一身的公主病
She even ordered everyone in the city
甚至還勒令全城的百姓官員
to treat her as a princess of the first rank.
喊她三公主
Princess of the first rank?
三公主
A city is too small for her, right?
一座城已經容不下她了是嗎
But I remember clearly
可是我明明安排
I told them to frighten the horse of
驚馬衝撞車隊之人
the Second Princess Chen Chuchu.
是二郡主陳楚楚
Why was it Chen Qianqian?
怎麼就變成陳芊芊了呢
What to do?
這該如何是好
Young Master.
少君
Act according to circumstances.
便宜行事
The hero saved the wrong person
英雄救美抱錯人
and the hero was taken for marriage by the female supporting role.
男主被女配搶親
I'm such a talented screenwriter
我是什麼樣的鬼才編劇
to create such an interesting story.
能寫出這樣的劇情
When will they transfer money for the script to me?
他們要多久給我轉稿費呀
Mr. Zhang.
張總
Xiaoqian,
小千啊
as for this script,
這個劇本呢
it can't be finalized for now.
咱們暫時還不能定稿啊
I see. I'd like to know...
明白 我就想問問我
The hero
就 就是咱們的男主角啊
Mr. Han said
韓老師那邊呢
he has some questions about it.
出了一點問題
Can you go there and communicate with him?
可能需要你過去溝通一下
As long as you convince him,
只要他那邊搞定了
we can begin the shooting.
咱們就可以開機了
Okay. I'd like to ask you about...
行 那我就問問我的那個
...the money for the script.
稿費
Who will pay me?
誰給我稿費
Everyone, please step back.
大家往後退一退啊
Don't push.
都別擠了
Don't bother them while they're working.
別影響工作
We're here!
我們在這裡呀
Hi, Mr. Han.
老師 你好
I'm the screenwriter of "The Tiger Sniffing the Rose",
我是那個猛虎嗅薔薇的編劇
Chen Xiaoqian.
陳小千
-Hi. -Hi.
你好 你好你好
I'll make a long story short.
我長話短說
I've read the script.
劇本我看了
I think something is wrong with the hero
我覺得男主角韓爍的人設
Han Shuo's character set.
還是有點問題
I see. What do you think... Mr. Han?
是 那您覺得 老師
Can you tell me what you think is wrong?
你覺得有什麼問題 您再
Mr. Han.
老師
What do you think is wrong?
您 您覺得有什麼問題啊 老師
Mr. Han, what's wrong with the character set?
老師 人物有什麼問題啊
Can you tell me what are Han Shuo's motives for doing that?
你說 韓爍的人物動機是什麼呢
As for his motives,
韓爍的人物動機呢
he wanted to get the Dragon Bone,
就是想要得到
Huayuan City's most precious treasure.
花垣城的鎮城之寶龍骨
As the Young Master of Xuanhu City,
因為韓爍是玄虎城的少城主
Han Shuo had heart disease from his childhood.
自小就患有心疾
He often had heart attacks.
心疾就是心臟病
Only the Dragon Bone could cure him.
只有龍骨才能治好他的病
So, Han Shuo agreed to marry into Huayuan City
韓爍就假意入贅花垣城
in order to get the Dragon Bone.
想要得到龍骨
In the end, he was killed by Chen Chuchu.
最後 還死在陳楚楚的劍下
Okay. Lift up.
來來來 起 起來
It's just that a hero often falls for a beauty.
他 他就是英雄難過美人關
That's the problem.
問題的關鍵就在這裡
Why did Han Shuo
韓爍怎麼就突然間
fall in love with Chen Chuchu suddenly?
喜歡上了陳楚楚
Just because she's the heroine?
就因為她是女主角
Excuse me. Okay.
大家讓一下 來
Well. Mr. Han. Look.
不是 老師 你看看
Okay. Lift up.
來 起
Because the heroine is clever,
因為女主角她聰明
quick-witted, beautiful and kind-hearted.
機智 漂亮 善良
Isn't that enough?
這還不夠嗎
Okay. Go refine his make-up.
來 上去 補妝
No.
不夠
A healthy relationship is based on equality.
愛情的基礎是平等
People in Huayuan City think men have to obey women.
花垣城的規矩是男人服從女人
It's quite the opposite for people in Xuanhu City.
玄虎城的規矩是女人服從男人
Such being the case,
我不覺得在這種設定下
I don't think Han Shuo would fall in love with a woman from Huayuan.
韓爍會去愛上花垣女人
Besides,
況且
Han Shuo is kind of
韓爍有那麼一點
a male chauvinist.
直男癌
A male chauvinist?
直 直男癌
Do you think we're equal?
那你覺得我們現在平等嗎
Okay. Down.
好 下
If two people are not equal,
不平等的兩個人
they couldn't even communicate,
連溝通都無法做到
let alone fall in love.
更別提相愛了
Just like you and me.
就像你跟我
Will you fall in love with me?
你會愛上我嗎
As for the feminism expressed in your script,
你在劇本里所表達的女權主義
in my opinion,
但在我看來
it's not different
這跟你所抨擊的男權
from the male chauvinism you criticized.
沒有什麼不同
The equality you look forward to
你所向往的平等
is not real equality.
不是真正的平等
Madam, you've never entered a relationship, right?
編劇老師沒談過戀愛吧
Get into a relationship if you have time.
有時間去談個戀愛
Then you'll be able to
這樣寫出來的情感戲
write a better love story.
才更加真實
Get started.
開始
Okay. Got it.
好 來
Up.
起
Okay. Lift up.
來 都起來 都起來
Mr. Zhang, I tried my best to cooperate,
張總 不是我不配合
but it was impossible to communicate with him.
是他根本就沒有辦法溝通
He flew away every time I wanted to say something.
我一說話 他就飛上去
I've even got a hoarse voice,
我嗓子都喊啞了
but he wouldn't listen to me.
他根本就不聽我的呀
Xiaoqian...
小千
Hold on.
你等一下
I think he's insane.
我覺得他就是有病
Hello? Mr. Zhang.
喂 張總
Xiaoqian.
小千
I thought about it carefully.
我剛剛仔細想過了
Go ahead.
你說
I'm too young.
的確是我太年輕了
I should've kept my bad mood from affecting my work.
不應該把情緒帶到工作中來的
Right.
對
Trust me.
你放心吧
As for the issues Mr. Han mentioned,
這演員老師說的問題呢
I'll correct them all.
我一定會改正的
The shooting won't be postponed.
一定不會拖延開機的
Trust me.
放心吧
Tens of thousands.
個 十 百 千 萬
It's just about relationships.
不就是愛情嗎
It's just about equality.
不就是平等嗎
Let me show you
讓你看看一個優秀的編劇
what an excellent screenwriter can do.
職業素養
Han Shuo killed Chen Qianqian and then deceived Chen Chuchu.
韓爍先殺陳芊芊 再騙陳楚楚
After being treated with the Dragon Bone, he began to rebel.
拿到龍骨治癒心疾就反手攻城
He conquered Huayuan,
滅了花垣
killed the City Owner and slaughtered the common people.
刺殺城主 屠戮百姓
He turned hostile all of a sudden.
翻臉比翻書還快啊
Han Shuo,
韓爍
I've never doubted you.
我從未懷疑過你
but you're so cruel.
但你卻如此狠心
You're so cruel as to treat me like that.
你卻如此狠心這樣對我
Chuchu,
楚楚
when I become the City Owner,
來日我繼位城主
you can continue to be my wife.
你可以繼續當我的城主夫人
Asshole.
渣男
No way.
不行不行不行
I can't write like this.
改掉
Han Shuo really fell in love
然而韓爍在和陳楚楚
with Chen Chuchu
假戲真做的時候
after starting it as a lie.
對她動了真心
He conquered Huayuan,
雖然攻佔了花垣
but he let Chuchu go.
卻還是放走了楚楚
After she escaped,
楚楚逃走之後
Chuchu endured hardships to plan retaliation.
臥薪嚐膽 捲土重來
In the end, they had to have a decisive battle.
最終還是 還是要決一死戰
They loved and hated each other. It's sad and weepy.
兩人愛恨糾葛 纏綿悱惻
I can't write like this.
不能這麼寫 不能這麼寫
I can't write a beautiful love story because I've never got in a relationship?
誰說不談戀愛就寫不來愛情戲
What a joke!
笑話
I can't catch a cold.
千萬別感冒啊
I haven't finished the script.
這劇本還沒寫完呢
Chen Chuchu, the Second Princess of Huayuan City,
花垣城二郡主陳楚楚
finally became the City Owner
歷經磨難
after going through hardships and setbacks.
終於登上城主之位
At her enthronement ceremony,
陳楚楚繼任大典上
the sun and the moon were up in the sky at the same time.
天降祥瑞 日月同輝
The gate to Heaven was wide open
天門大開
and radiant splendor appeared.
異彩漫天
I'm sleepy.
好睏
It's hard to be a screenwriter.
當編劇可真難
I had a good sleep just because the script was done.
寫完稿子就是睡得踏實
Chen Xiaoqian.
陳小千
What did you do?
你飄了呀
You just got paid
你掙了點錢
and you dared to come to a nightclub for fun?
你就敢來夜店消費了
And you even did cos-play.
你還玩角色扮演
Get up. Hurry.
起來起來 趕緊起來
Her Highness woke up. She's dashing wine glasses.
三公主醒了 摔酒杯呢
Whatever. I've spent lots of money anyway.
蝨子多了不怕癢
I don't care.
不心疼 不心疼
It must be expensive.
這得多少錢
Your Highness, let us pay our respects to you.
給三公主問安
Thank you for your patronage.
謝三公主惠顧
What's your price?
大家 多少錢啊
For me, it's 1,000 taels of gold per song.
小的一曲千金
900 for me.
小的一曲九百
800 for me.
小的一曲八百
But Your Highness,
但是三公主您想聽曲的話
you can get all this for free.
小的通通免費
For free?
免費
Well. What did you call me just now?
不是 你剛才叫我什麼
Your Highness?
三公主
Your... Highness?
三 三公主
Let me have a look.
我看一下啊
What a coincidence.
不會這麼巧吧
A lotus bracelet with a small bell.
蓮花鐲配鈴鐺
This is a kind of special accessory of musicians
這是我劇本里
in the Music and Dance Academy in my script.
教坊司的樂人才有的配飾啊
Could it be
難道
here is...
這裡是
Your Highness.
三公主 三公主
This dream looks familiar.
這個夢好眼熟啊
I wrote it?
我寫的
Oh no.
完了
I'm trapped in the script I wrote.
我卡在自己寫的劇本里了
My script tells
我的劇本里
a story that happened in Huayuan City,
故事發生在一個
a place where women had the decisive say.
女人當家做主的花垣城
In Huayuan City,
在這裡
women enjoyed higher status
女人天生金貴
than men.
而男人 地位卑劣
If a couple had a baby girl, they'd be wild with joy.
普通人家得一女 如獲至寶
Congratulations.
生了生了
It's a baby girl.
女孩
A baby boy again.
又是個男孩
You good-for-nothing.
你這個廢物
Do you want me to die without descendants?
你這是要絕我們家的後
In Huayuan City,
在花垣
both civil and military officials
無論是文官還是武職
were women.
皆由女人擔任
Men couldn't secure an official position.
男人不能做官
And they didn't have the right to be educated.
也沒有讀書認字的資格
Want to study? In your dreams.
想讀書 沒那個命啊
You'd better think about marrying into a rich family.
還不如想著找個好人家
Go. Get to work.
快走 幹活去
Hurry.
快點快點
Innocence is a virtue for men.
有道是男子無才便是德
There were five social classes: scholars, farmers, artisans, merchants and men,
社會階級按照士農工商男
ranked in descending order.
依次遞減
-It can be said that, -He shirked at work,
可以說
-men were at the bottom of the social ladder. -discipline him better at home.
男人們處於社會的最底層
So little?
這麼少的
You...
你呀
I'll teach you a good lesson after we go back.
看我回去怎麼收拾你
In Huayuan City,
在花垣城
all singers and dancers
就連出來賣藝的歌舞演員
were men.
都是男的
Come on.
給我嘛
Sell it to me.
賣給我嘛
You have good skin.
這細皮嫩肉的
I can't believe I became the Third Princess of Huayuan City,
我居然變成了花垣城三公主
Chen Qianqian.
陳芊芊
The one who called herself the princess of the first rank.
管自己叫三公主的陳芊芊
The one who took Han Shuo for marriage by force
就是那個街頭搶親
and was poisoned by him
結果大婚當日就被男主韓爍
on their wedding night.
一杯毒酒送上西天
The cameo role who died in the third episode.
第三集就領了盒飯的女炮灰
Which episode is it?
現在是第幾集
Which episode?
第幾集
Well. I meant
就是 我的意思就是說
what's the situation now.
現在故事發展到哪裡了
Situation?
故事
What does she mean?
這什麼意思
Your Highness.
三公主
Your wedding dress is sent here.
喜服到了
What?
喜服
Your Highness,
我的三公主
you're getting married today.
今天可是您大婚的日子
We worked against the clock
小的們是緊趕慢趕
to complete the embroidered wedding dress in time.
才做出來的滿繡飄金的喜服
Please try it on to see if it fits you.
快 試試合不合身
Episode three?
第三集啊
I'm telling you.
我告訴你
Take it away now.
你趕緊把這個東西拿走
This is not a wedding dress, but a mourning dress.
這不是喜服 這是喪服
Besides, I won't marry Han Shuo.
而且我是不會跟韓爍大婚的
He's a jinx.
他這個掃把星
I have to stay away from him.
我得離他越遠越好
Take it away.
拿走
But it...
不是 這
Young Master,
少君
the wedding procession has been staying at the gate since last night.
迎親的隊伍從昨夜一直守在門口
They said they're here to protect us,
說是保護我們
but actually, they're keeping eyes on us.
其實就是監視
I've been waiting here for a long time
下官奉玄虎城主之命
under the order of your father.
在此恭候少君多時
Young Master, she's one of us.
少君 自己人
What on earth has happened?
到底發生何事
Why did something unforeseen happen
為何少君一進城
once you entered the city?
就發生如此變故
I...
我
I was ordered by Young Master Han
我原本按照少君之意
to get close to the Second Princess Chen Chuchu,
是設計接近二郡主陳楚楚
since she's the best candidate
因為畢竟她才是百姓
for the City Owner
和官員心目當中
in the minds of the common people and officials.
少城主的最佳人選
Only through getting close to her can we get the Dragon Bone
接近她才能得到龍骨
to cure Young Master Han.
救治少君的心疾
But unexpectedly,
可萬萬沒想到的是
it was Chen Qianqian's horse
這驚馬之人
that got frightened.
竟變成了三公主陳芊芊
Young Master Han saved the wrong person
少君救錯了人
and hit her fancy.
被搶了親
It seems that someone doesn't want me
看來有人不希望
to have anything to do with Chen Chuchu.
我與陳楚楚有所瓜葛
I guess someone let it happen on purpose.
許是有人刻意安排的
Young Master,
少君
is it the City Owner of Huayuan?
難道是花垣城的城主
Nothing is known yet.
一切還未可知
I showed weakness by pretending to have heart attacks.
我藉著心疾示弱
I hope people here
或許能降低
can lower their guard.
花垣城眾人對我的警惕
Young Master, please don't worry.
少君放心
As long as you give an order,
只要您一聲令下
all secret spies hidden in Huayuan City
潛伏在花垣城內的密探
will keep you safe
定護您周全
and stop the Third Princess having her way.
不會讓那個三公主得逞的
Here. Have a look. It's cheap.
來 看一看啊 便宜了
Young Master, are you okay?
少君 您無礙吧
It doesn't matter.
無妨
I won't have a heart attack that easily.
我的心疾沒有這麼輕易發作
What shall we do next?
那接下來我們該怎麼辦
Push the boat along with the current.
順水推舟
Now that the Third Princess is eager to marry me,
既然這三公主這麼想與我成婚
let's do as she wishes.
那就如她所願
I'll poison Chen Qianqian tonight
今晚毒殺陳芊芊
to get rid of her.
先掃清這個障礙
Then we'll go with the original plan,
隨後按原計劃
help Chen Chuchu succeed her mother
扶持陳楚楚上位
and use her to get the Dragon Bone.
利用她奪得龍骨
When I get Huayuan's rare treasure
待我奪得花垣城祕寶
and my heart disease is cured,
治癒心疾後
I'll light up the fire beacons on the lookout tower.
便立刻點燃瞭望臺上的狼煙
Then our armies will be sent here
屆時玄虎揮師南下
to conquer Huayuan City.
一舉攻佔花垣
Young Master, you're so wise.
少君英明
Kill all those who failed their work this time.
將此次辦事不力的人通通殺了
Young Master,
少君
we're in the enemy camp. We may get into trouble anytime.
如今我們身處敵營 危險重重
Please think it over
還請少君三思啊
and give those who made mistakes,
給犯錯的人
especially me,
尤其是我
a chance to make amends.
一個將功補過的機會吧
Then find out the chief culprit of
那就找出搞砸此次
this accident.
驚馬事件的罪魁禍首
Kill him as a warning to others.
殺一儆百
Yes, Young Master!
屬下領命
Young Master,
少君
the chief culprit has been killed.
罪魁禍首已然處置
You...
你
Who told you to kill the horse?
誰讓你殺馬了
He had the horse killed?
他把馬殺了
It's a warning to me.
這是殺馬儆我呀
I'll be the next one.
下一個就輪到我了
Xuanhu?
玄虎
A small city
邊陲小城
at the border.
彈丸之地
They even sent their Young Master here
自己家的少君
as a hostage.
都被送過來當質子了
There is nothing to be afraid of.
還有什麼可囂張的
Han Shuo is seriously ill.
韓少君病病歪歪的
Obviously, he's a worthless person.
看著就是個廢人
He could only vent his anger on a horse.
還拿馬發上脾氣了
In the end,
最後啊
he'll be ordered about by you.
還不是任您擺弄嗎
At the border?
邊陲
A small city?
彈丸
Worthless?
廢人
Ordered about by me?
任我擺弄
I'm telling you.
我告訴你啊
If you want to survive,
你要是想活命
never say those words in the presence of Han Shuo.
就別把這些話當著韓爍面說
Of course I won't.
那是自然不會了
In case
倘若
I really offend Han Shuo,
我要真把韓少君惹怒了
you'll keep me safe, right?
三公主你不得護著我呀
I can't even keep myself safe,
我自己我都護不住
let alone you.
我護你我
If I do as the plot says,
我要是順著劇情
drink the poisoned wine on our wedding night
在洞房之夜喝了韓爍的毒酒
and die,
領了盒飯
will I wake up?
我是不是就能醒過來
Your Highness,
三公主
let me tell you
我給你講述一下
about the procedures of your wedding ceremony.
今日大婚的全部流程
Listen carefully.
你仔細聽聽
You don't like these unnecessary formalities,
您素來不喜歡這些繁文縟節
but it's a different case this time.
但這回不同啊
Since your mother got married,
自從城主大婚
no wedding ceremonies have been held
咱們花垣城已經整整三十多年
for over 30 years in Huayuan City.
沒有舉辦過婚儀了
This time, you'll marry the Young Master of Xuanhu.
這次又是和玄虎兩城聯姻
The ceremony will be grander.
規模更為盛大
I don't want to mention anything else for now.
別的咱不說
Just the flower parade
就說這花車遊街
will include 64 horses...
足足六十四乘的儀
You're Zi Rui, right?
你是梓銳吧
To reach the necessary word count,
當初為了增加字數
I gave you lots of lines.
給你身上加了好多詞
Will you always be a chatter-box?
你不會一直這麼囉唆吧
I'm telling you.
我告訴你啊
From now on,
從現在開始
you can say no more than ten characters each time.
你每句話只能說 十個字
But...
不是
Tell me about the procedures. In ten characters.
現在什麼流程 十個字
Flower parade.
花車遊街
With the Second Princess.
與二郡主一起
Cancel the flower parade. I'm not going.
花車遊街免了 不去了
What?
免了
Your Highness,
我的三公主啊
it's unprecedented.
這 這史無前例呀
I'm telling you.
我告訴你
What matters the most
現在最重要的
is to marry Han Shuo.
就是跟韓爍成親
Except for drinking "cross-cupped" wine,
除了喝交杯酒
everything else can be cancelled.
其他的全部都可以免去
Then how will we explain it
那 那如何跟城主
to your mother and your sister?
還有二郡主交代
It's easy.
這還不好說
Just tell them I'm burning with anxiety.
你就說我 心急如焚
I can't wait to celebrate the wedding with Han Shuo.
著急跟韓爍洞房
What?
什麼
The flower parade is cancelled?
花車遊街免了
Your Highness,
回稟二郡主
it's said that Han Shuo is eager to
說是驛站傳來消息
celebrate the wedding with the Third Princess.
韓少君急著與三公主洞房
Everyone thinks
眾人議論
the Third Princess was the one who can't wait.
是三公主偏好美色 性急
Zi Zhu,
梓竹
Qianqian is my younger sister.
芊芊是我妹妹
Stop discussing her without respect.
豈能妄議
Please forgive me.
小人知錯
It couldn't be better
韓爍若是良配
if Han Shuo is the right guy for her.
也再好不過
In this case,
芊芊成婚後
Qianqian will be more mature.
就能安穩些吧
Young...
少
Young Master.
少君
The poison is called "Soul Missing Powder."
此毒名為斷魂散
It's colorless and odorless after dissolving in water.
入水無色無味
Victims will die a sudden death during their sleep,
中毒者會在睡夢之中暴斃而死
before anyone else knows it.
殺人於無形
Trust me.
您放心
No matter how they investigate it,
他們怎麼查
they couldn't think it has anything to do with you.
都查不到您的頭上
There is one more thing.
還有個事
I heard
屬下聽聞
Chen Qianqian's only strength is
這三公主唯一可取之處
that she's good at Kung Fu.
就是功夫了得
Take this with you,
您帶上這個
just in case.
以防萬一
If anything happens,
如有不測
you can prevent yourself being hurt.
少君的清白最重要
If something really happens between her and me tonight,
要是今晚我跟她發生了什麼
who do you think will be hurt?
你覺得是誰佔誰的便宜
I've thought too much.
屬下多慮了
Chen Qianqian is brutal and domineering,
陳芊芊暴虐成性 刁蠻專橫
but her mother is indulgent with her.
花垣城主卻偏寵此人
Tonight,
今晚
I have to kill her.
她死有餘辜
Young Master, you're wise.
少君英明
Young Master,
稟告少君
the Third Princess just ordered
三公主剛剛交代
to cancel the flower parade.
花車遊街免了
What?
免了
As the Young Master of Xuanhu City,
我們少君乃一城少主
Young Master Han deserves the grandest reception.
當以最隆重的禮儀接待
How can she cancel it at will?
豈能說免就免
The Third Princess also asked us
三公主還交代
to take Young Master Han to Yueli Mansion directly
將韓少君直接送入月璃府
so that they can celebrate the wedding immediately.
立即洞房
Young Master Han, this way please.
少君 請吧
Ridiculous.
豈有此理
Outrageous.
成何體統
How can a bride be so impatient?
哪有大婚當日女子急不可耐的
Bai Ji,
白芨
let's do as Her Highness said.
就依三公主的
Young Master.
少君
What's the next procedure?
接下來呢 什麼流程
Offering sacrifice to Heaven.
祭天
Praying for permanent peace.
祭告上天 永保長寧
Don't bother.
不用了
I don't need to tell God I'm getting married.
結個婚不用跟老天爺說了
Cancel it.
祭天也免了
Take him here directly.
趕緊洞房
The Third Princess and our Young Master
三公主和我們公子
had been engaged to each other in their childhood.
是從小就定下的姻緣
How can she marry the Young Master of Xuanhu
怎麼這般不顧及公子的臉面
and make our Young Master lose face?
讓玄虎的少城主搶了先
What will he do
她那邊成婚了
now that she's married?
我們公子怎麼辦
Lower your voice.
小聲點
Don't let him hear it.
別讓公子聽到了
You know,
他呀
he hates it the most
最不喜歡我們提起
when we mention his engagement to the Third Princess.
他跟三公主的婚事
It doesn't matter.
不妨事
I heard Young Master Han had heart disease
聽說韓少君患有心疾
and couldn't live to 20.
活不過二十歲
Our Young Master can afford to wait.
我們公子可等得起
He'll survive that guy.
看誰熬過誰
Minister Pei,
裴司學
The Third Princess asked me to tell you
三公主派小人傳話
she'll keep everything simple for her wedding.
婚禮一切從簡
Sacrifice to Heaven
祭天
will be cancelled.
免了
So, the prayer for the ceremony will...
這祭天禱文 也
Okay. I see.
好 我知道了
Don't you want to know why?
公子不問緣由嗎
The Third Princess is unlearned and ignores rites.
三公主胸無點墨 罔顧禮法
Now that she wants to cancel it, let it go.
不愛祭天 就隨她去吧
It can save me the trouble of praising her in the article.
我也省些誇讚她的筆墨詞句
I'll take my leave.
那小人告退了
What's the next procedure?
接下來什麼流程
Go to see the City Owner, that is, your mother.
面見城主 以告父母
Cancel it.
直接洞房
Your Majesty.
城主
What's up?
何事
The Third Princess passed on a message.
三公主傳話來
She said you have to attend to numerous affairs every day,
說您日理萬機
so she wouldn't bother you with a petty thing like getting married.
成親這種小事就不叨擾您了
She's running wild.
胡鬧
I also thought it was improper.
下官也覺得不妥
I've sent someone to her mansion.
已經派人去請了
She's been arrogant and willful since childhood.
這孩子 自幼驕縱
She's even more self-willed.
如今越發任性了
Your Majesty.
城主啊
Perhaps the Third Princess
這三公主
just thinks the formalities are unnecessary.
可能只是覺得禮數繁冗
Fine.
罷了
Let her cancel it.
免了就免了
It's no big deal.
也不是什麼大不了的事情
Yes, Your Majesty.
是
This Young Master Han
這韓少君
is in poor health,
身子骨不太硬朗
and the Third Princess
咱家三公主
is not that thoughtful.
又是一個不太精細的人
What if anything happens
這萬一要有個好歹
and Han Shuo fails to tough it out?
這韓少君 沒挺過去
Leave it to fate.
萬般皆是命
Just consider as that Qianqian helps me out.
就當芊芊替我排憂解難了
You'll get a divorce in the following cases: you're not obedient to the in-laws;
不順父母者出
you fail to have a female heir;
膝下無女者出
you have an affair;
不安於室者出
you're jealous...
凶悍妒忌者出
You contract infectious disease;
身患惡疾者出
you're a big mouth and love to gossip;
搬弄是非者出
you're against rules and regulations.
不合規矩者出
The seven conditions are the seven grounds
這七條
for lawfully divorcing a man in Huayuan City.
是花垣男子的七出之罪
I've remembered them.
韓某已經背過了
Young Master...
少君
This is also a custom in Huayuan City.
這也是花垣城的習俗
The bridegroom will follow the one
新婚之夜
who takes off his veil
誰將男子的面巾取下
on the wedding night.
男子就要追隨於誰
It'll be considered unchaste if he follows someone else.
易主 視為不貞
As for this,
這一條
I can comply with it too.
韓某也可以照做
Absurd.
荒唐
How dare you
你們花垣城
ask men to follow these rules?
怎麼可以如此約束男子
The status of women in Xuanhu City
女人在玄虎城什麼地位
is the status of men
男人
in Huayuan City.
在我們花垣城就是什麼地位
You bi...
你個老
Bai Ji,
白芨
when in Rome, do as the Romans do.
入鄉隨俗
What is it?
這又是何物
Gecko cinnabar.
守宮砂
How dare you?
放肆
I decided to get married to the Third Princess
韓某與三公主成婚
to ease the relationship
為的是緩和
between Xuanhu and Huayuan.
玄虎和花垣兩城的關係
As for men's virtues and the veil,
什麼夫德 面巾
I've tried my best to be tolerant.
韓某都一再忍讓
But you're pressing at every stage.
爾等卻步步緊逼
You're...
簡直
You're going too far in bullying them.
欺人太甚
Young Master.
少君
Why bother with the gecko cinnabar?
這會兒點什麼守宮砂呀
Even if you leave a red mark now,
這會兒點了
it'll be gone after I sleep with him tonight.
洞了房之後還能剩下什麼呀
There is no point of doing that.
你家守宮砂日拋的呀
You're right, Your Highness.
是是是 三公主
I'm leaving.
小的這就告退
Young Master Han.
韓少君
Young Master.
少君
I'm not leaving.
我不走
Young Master Han, shall we go through the motions
韓少君 我們是走個過場呢
or
還是
get right to the point?
直接進入正題啊
It's our wedding night.
大婚之夜
How could we not drink to add to the fun?
怎麼能少了喝酒助興呢
"Cross-cupped" wine.
交杯
I need to pay attention to my posture
還得注意姿勢
to drink the poisoned wine.
喝有毒的那杯
Qianqian,
三公主
we met each other yesterday
你我昨日有緣初遇
and we got married today.
今日就要結為夫妻
I hope we can support each other
之後定當相互扶持
and share joys and hardships together.
同甘共苦
Fine.
也好
In this case, I can go home soon.
這樣我就能早點回家了
Cheers.
幹了
What's the matter?
少君這是怎麼了
I'm sorry
抱歉
for having your spirits dampened.
掃了三公主雅興
Sorry.
不好意思啊
Let's do it again.
重來一次
Cheers.
幹了
What's wrong this time?
又怎麼了
Isn't it a posture
這 這不是按照玄虎城
people in Xuanhu are used to?
習慣的姿勢來的嗎
You want to take the veil off, right?
面紗沒摘是吧
So much trouble.
真麻煩
Why is it tied so tight?
卡這麼緊幹嗎呀這
Why is it you?
怎麼是你
Didn't you say you don't want to act as him?
你不是說你不演嗎
I don't know what you're talking about.
韓某不知三公主何意
Could it be that
難道
you think I poisoned your wine?
是懷疑我在酒中下毒
As for this matter,
酒裡有沒有毒
you know it best.
你心裡沒點數啊
Drop the act.
還跟我裝
Fine. It's not poisoned, right?
行 沒毒是吧
Okay. Pick one. Let's drink it up.
來 挑一杯吧 咱倆幹了
Let me tell you the truth.
實話告訴你
Even if I die today,
今天就算是我死了
I'll take you with me.
我也得帶走你
Servants!
來人啊
Here.
來了
I don't want to talk to you.
懶得跟你說
Your Highness, what can I do for you?
三公主 有何吩咐
Lift him up.
把他吊起來
He likes to stay in the air.
他喜歡在上面待著
Lift him up?
吊起來
Your Highness,
三公主
today is your wedding day.
你大婚之日
Don't make trouble,
惹出這麼大的動靜
or your mother will be worried.
城主知道又該擔心了
Please think it over.
您三思
She'll be worried even if I don't make trouble.
不惹麻煩她就不擔心了嗎
Besides, I didn't aim to do that,
再說了 今天不是我惹麻煩
but, he wanted to poison me.
是他 要下毒殺我
Your Highness, why are you saying that?
三公主 此話怎講
You don't believe?
不信是吧
You don't believe, right?
你們不信是吧
Fine. Let me prove it to you.
好 我證明給你看
The two poisoned glasses of wine are evidence.
這兩杯毒酒就是證據
I'm telling you.
我告訴你
If I die today,
我今天死在這兒
you couldn't survive.
你也別想活
You poisoned the dishes, right?
把毒下菜裡了是吧
Good idea.
有想法啊
Great.
特別有想法
Your Highness,
三公主
what are you doing?
此舉何意啊
I'd like to see where else you can hide the poison.
我看你還能把毒藏在哪兒
Salty.
鹹 鹹了
Did he smear it on his lips?
難道 毒藥抹嘴上了
It turns out you're a drama king.
你挺會給自己加戲呀
You!
你
Tell me
你告訴我
if I'm bound to die.
我現在是不是死定了
Yes, definitely.
你現在絕對死定了
Zi Rui,
梓銳
if I die,
一會兒我死了
tear his body up by five horses and implicate the nine generations of his family.
你就五馬分屍 誅他九族
Got it?
明白了嗎
Young Master Han, why don't you explain to her?
韓少君 你為何不辯駁
Don't listen to him.
你不要聽他辯
I...
我
Zi Rui,
梓銳
so many of you
我現在看你已經是好多個你
are waggling here before my eyes.
在這兒晃悠
I feel the poison
我感覺到毒性已經運
has attacked my brain.
運行到我大腦了
I'm dying.
完了完了
I can't control my tongue.
舌頭也捋不直了
Oh no. My head is spinning.
我的媽 不能再暈了
I need to sit down.
坐 坐 坐
Let me lie down for a while.
我躺一會兒
Your poison has a strong delayed effect.
你 你的毒藥後勁挺大
Go get the doctor!
快 叫大夫
Young Master.
少君
Your Highness.
三公主